Finding Aid for Janette Estelle Miller papers, 1886-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Janette Estelle Miller papers 1886-1970
Miller, Janette Estelle, 1879-1969
85329 Aa 2
Congregationalist missionary to Angola, and other members of the Miller family. Family letters, missionary newsletter, personal diaries concerning life in Hancock and Detroit, Michigan; Miller family materials; and photographs.
2 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Arthur Miller (donor no. 6097 ) a nephew of Janette Miller, in 1977.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Janette Miller was a Congregationalist missionary to Angola.
The collection consists of personal papers of Janette Miller and other members of the Miller family. The collection includes family letters, missionary newsletter, personal diaries concerning life in Hancock and Detroit, Michigan, photographs, and Miller family materials.
Subjects:
Africa.; Angola.; Congregational churches.; Detroit (Mich.); Hancock (Mich.); Michigan--Social life and customs--1881-1890.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; Miller, Janette, 1879-1969.; Miller family.; Missionaries--Angola.; Congregational churches--Missions--Angola.; Michigan--Social life and customs--19th century.; Michigan--Social life and customs--20th century.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Africa--Missions.; Angola.; Battle Creek (Mich.)--Railroad stations.; Birmingham (Mich.); Canoes.; Children.; Churches--Michigan--Hancock.; Detroit Steel Products Company.; Hancock (Mich.); Hancock (Mich.)--Churches.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Interiors.; Kalamazoo River (Mich.); Macatawa (Mich.); Michigan Union.; Miller, Frank White.; Miller family.; Missions--Africa.; Parades and processions.; Portage Lake Ship Canal (Mich.); Railroad stations--Michigan--Battle Creek.; University of Michigan--Block M--1901-1910.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; Winter.; Wood family.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Drawings.; Paintings.; Photographs.
- Janette E. Miller papers
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1898-1919 (Box 1)
    - 1920-1928 (Box 1)
    - 1930-1935 (Box 1)
    - 1936-1939 (Box 1)
    - 1949, 1950, 1952, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Missionary newsletters
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1920-February 1921 (Box 1)
    - March 1921-July 1921 (Box 1)
    - February-June 1922 (Box 1)
    - July-October 1922 (Box 1)
    - September 1923-September 1924 (Box 1)
    - 1925-May 1927 (Box 1)
    - September 1927-November 1929 (Box 1)
    - 1930 (Box 1)
    - 1931-1933 (Box 1)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 1)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 1)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 1)
    - 1940 (Box 1)
    - 1954-1958 (Box 1)
    - February 1960 January 1970 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous mission materials, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of printed missionary materials (Box 1)
  - Diaries
    (combination of journal photograph album, and scrapbook)
    - 1886-1895 (Box 1)
      (includes photos of children and Hancock, Michigan, including Congregational Church and canal; also drawings)
    - 1894 (Box 1)
    - 1896-1897 (Box 1)
    - 1901 (Box 1)
    - 1902 (Box 1)
    - 1903 (Box 1)
    - 1904 (Box 1)
    - 1905 (Box 1)
    - 1906 (Box 1)
    - 1907 (Box 1)
    - 1908 (Box 1)
      (includes photos of rural Birmingham, Michigan)
    - 1909 (Box 1)
      (includes photos of Macatawa, Michigan, and Huron River canoeing)
  - Photographs
    - Africa, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Africa postcards and prints (Box 2)
    - Family and friends (Box 2)
      (includes photo of Battle Creek railroad station)
    - Loose photos from diaries (Box 2)
    - Portraits of Janette Miller (Box 2)
    - Watercolor paintings (Box 2)
- Miller family
  - Genealogy (Box 2)
  - Genealogical and family materials, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Joseph Miller papers (Box 2)
  - Eli Miller papers (Box 2)
  - Harriet Miller (wife of Eli Miller) papers (Box 2)
  - Charles Miller (father of Janette Miller) papers
    - General (Box 2)
    - Essay, "My Secret of Success" (Box 2)
    - Estate materials (Box 2)
  - Frank Miller (brother of Janette Miller) papers (Box 2)
  - Papers re Old Miller Farm, Richland, Michigan (Box 2)
  - Papers re Wood family (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan student scrapbook of Frank Miller 1904-1909 (Box 2)
    (includes photos of student scenes, Block M, an Ann Arbor restaurant, and the Union Circus parade)
  - Arthur Miller (nephew of Janette Miller) service papers with US Maritime Service (Box 2)
  - Photographs
    - Miller, Arthur (Box 2)
    - Miller, Frank
      - Children (Box 2)
      - Groups (Box 2)
        (includes photos of canoeing and tobogganing)
      - Individuals, Identified (Box 2)
      - Individuals Unidentified (Box 2)
        (includes photos of canoeing)
      - Portraits (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
        (includes photos of canoeing and Detroit Steel Products Co. Safety Committee)
    - Miller family, 2 folders (Box 2)
      (includes photo of Kalamazoo River)
    - Wood family (Box 2)